Venkat Hanuman Rao Suragani

Phone: +91 9394076332 | Email: hanuman.suragani@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/hanuman-suragani https://hanuman-suragani.github.io/

Professional Summary:

A passionate analyst with strong research experience and an Engineering Management graduate from Australia with special interest in *Business Analyst* roles. Have strong written and oral communication skills alongside the ability to take-up tasks and perform professionally as a team leader and an individual player.

Skills

- Excellent written and oral communication skills.
- MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, MS Project.
- Good presentation skills.
- Incisive and quick learner.
- User stories and Agile methodology.
- Power Bi

Work Experience

Transaction Risk Analyst

May 2021 - Current

Amazon-Hyderabad, India.

- Keep abreast of trends and fraud issues impacting the retail industry.
- Continuously identify, assess and enhance fraud management policies, procedures, process design and controls pertaining to US-marketplace.
- Observing customer transactions to identify fraudulent activities such as account take over, friendly fraud, ID theft and limiting the error percentage in US\$ to less than 1%.
- Interacting with banks and customers to validate information and to confirm or cancel authorizations.

Customer service Supervisor

Feb 2019 - Feb 2020

Caltex Pvt Ltd, Victoria, Australia.

- Inventory Management of in-store stock worth more than 100,000 AUD a month.
- Used to lead a team of more than 30 employees.
- Implementing timely strategies to upsell the stock effectively and training the employees for the same and tracking and inventory for loss prevention
- Effectively worked towards increasing Quarter on Quarter sales by 12%(avg), summing more than 2Million AUD/month.

Store Manager (Part-Time)

May 2018 - Jan 2019

United Petroleum, Bacchus Marsh, Victoria, Australia.

- Analyzing monthly KPI reports and planning future strategies for better growth in sales.
- Administering weekly meetings with Business Managers and assessing weekly variations.
- Dealing with various supply chain organizations and vendors across numerous platforms.
- Successfully managed to retain the customer base by implementing loyal customer benefits and increase by the annual net-sales by 16%.
- Increased the net-revenue of the company by cutting down the costs by analyzing customer trends.

Education

Masters in Engineering Management

Oct 2017 - Aug 2019

Deakin University, Waurn Ponds campus

• Major: Electronics and Engineering Management

Bachelor of Technology

Sep 2012 - Apr 2016

JNTUH college of Engineering.

• Major: Electronics and Communication Engineering.

Extra-curricular Mentions

- Head of the Designing Committee and Advertising Committee in the National Technical Fest "AGRATHA-2015" at JNTUH(Hyderabad-India)
- Selected in the "Academia Student Interaction-2016" held **at National Remote Sensing Centre** (NRSC), Hyderabad, India-one of the centers of "*Indian Space Research Organization*" (ISRO).
- Lead a team workshop conducted by "ROBOVERSITY"-an Alumni of Indian Institute of Technology Kanpur.

Volunteer Work

Member Dec 2015 - Mar 2016

National Service Scheme (NSS), JNTUH-CES, Hyderabad, India

- Organized several awareness programs for economically weaker sections about sanitation.
- Managing several meetings with local bank authorities and establishing a local branch in the university so that the villages around can get awareness from the campus and the students.

Team Leader Mar 2014 - Apr 2016

SAHAYEE, Medak, India - A non-profit welfare association.

- Raising funds towards stationery school supplies for five government schools.
- Imparting knowledge to school children about the significance of computer and internet.
- Organizing scheduled meetings with funding societies and other team members.

<u>Additional Information</u>.

Languages: English, Telugu, Hindi

Age: 26 years.

Interests: Photography, Trekking and Cricket.